Guide to the Chester Alan Arthur Scrapbooks
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Chester Alan Arthur Scrapbooks
1881-1885
Arthur, Chester Alan, 1829-1886.
19 linear ft (76 v. housed in 38 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078698
Biographical Note
President of the United States, 1881-1885.
Scope and Content
Newspaper clippings relating to the career, life, activities, and political milieu of Chester A. Arthur, compiled for him while he was president, and covering only the period of his presidency. The clippings are mounted in 76 volumes and were gathered from both the major New York papers had local and specialized journals from all over the country. The volumes are grouped in several sequences as follows: 45 volumes labelled "Current Comment" 1881-1885; 6 volumes "Presidential Predictions, 1883-1884; 7 volumes "Canal and foreign questions," 1881-1885; 2 volumes "Personal," 1882-1883; 3 volumes "Appointments," 1882-1885; 3 volumes "Conventions," 1881-1884; 2 volumes "Civil Service," 1881-1885; 2 volumes "Mormonism," 1881-1885; 2 volumes "Southern," 1881-1884; 1 volume "Financial and Statistical," 1881-1885; 1 volume "Tariff discussions," 1884-1885; 1 volume "Social," 1884-1885; 1 volume "Miscellaneous notes," 1884-1885.
Arrangement
Chronological within each volume.
Subjects
Southern States.; United States--Officials and employees.; United States--Politics and government--1881-1885.; United States--Foreign relations.; Civil service.; Customs administration.; Mormon Church.; Presidents--United States.; Scrapbooks.; Politicians.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
M55-01
- Series I: Scrapbooks
  - Current Comments, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Current Comments, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 3 & 4)
  - Current Comments, 1881 (Box 3, Folder 5 & 6)
  - Current Comments, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 7 & 8)
  - Current Comments, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 9 & 10)
  - Current Comments, 1882 (Box 6, Folder 11 & 12)
  - Current Comments, 1882 (Box 7, Folder 13 & 14)
  - Current Comments, 1882 (Box 8, Folder 15 & 16)
  - Current Comments, 1882 (Box 9, Folder 17 & 18)
  - Current Comments, 1882 (Box 10, Folder 19 & 20)
  - Current Comments, 1882 (Box 11, Folder 21 & 22)
  - Current Comments, 1882 (Box 12, Folder 23 & 24)
  - Current Comments, 1883 (Box 13, Folder 25 & 26)
  - Current Comments, 1883 (Box 14, Folder 27 & 28)
  - Current Comments, 1883 (Box 15, Folder 29 & 30)
  - Current Comments, 1883 (Box 16, Folder 31 & 32)
  - Current Comments, 1884 (Box 17, Folder 33 & 34)
  - Current Comments, 1884 (Box 18, Folder 35 & 36)
  - Current Comments, 1884 (Box 19, Folder 37 & 38)
  - Current Comments, 1884 (Box 20, Folder 39 & 40)
  - Current Comments, 1884 (Box 21, Folder 41 & 42)
  - Current Comments, 1885 (Box 22, Folder 44 & 45)
  - Presidential Predictions, 1883 (Box 23, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Presidential Predictions, 1883/1884 (Box 24, Folder 3 & 4)
  - Presidential Predictions, 1883/1884 (Box 25, Folder 5 & 7)
  - Presidential Predictions, 1884 (Box 26, Folder Volume 8)
  - Conventions, 1881 (Box 26, Folder Volume 1)
  - Conventions, 1881-1884 (Box 27, Folder 2 & 3)
  - Civil Service, 1881-1885 (Box 28, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Social, 1884/1885 (Box 29, Folder Volume 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1884/1885 (Box 29, Folder Volume 1)
  - Mormonisn, 1881-1885 (Box 30, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Financial & Statistical, 1881-1885 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Tariff Discussion, 1884/1885 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Southern, 1881-1884 (Box 32, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Canal & Foreign Questions, 1882 (Box 33, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Canal & Foreign Questions, 1882 (Box 34, Folder 3 & 4)
  - Canal & Foreign Questions, 1882-1885 (Box 35, Folder 5 & 6)
  - Canal & Foreign Questions, 1882 (Box 36, Folder Volume 7)
  - Appointments, 1882 (Box 36, Folder Volume 1)
  - Appointments, 1882-1885 (Box 37, Folder 2 & 3)
  - Personal, 1882/1883 (Box 38, Folder 1 & 2)